Danny Yu | Software Engineer

Former insurance underwriter turned Software Engineer, with experience in developing rapport, explaining terminology and highlighting the unique benefits between the many products the company offers. Coordinated with multiple teams within the company to deliver a complete product in a timely manner to satisfy everyone and most importantly the client. As a Software Engineer, I will use my background to find solutions that will benefit the company and its end-users.

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other: RESTful Routing, JSON API
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Flask

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

 $\textbf{SpaceCommerce} \mid [\underline{GitHub}] \mid [\underline{Deployed}] \mid | \ MongoDB, \ Express, \ React, \ Node$

(11/2022 - 11/2022)

E-Commerce Website for Celestial Objects

- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) to build a full stack application in 5 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all golden 7 RESTful API calls.
- Backend database is deployed with Railway and Atlas MongoDB. Tested API routes using Postman to ensure functionality during production.
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using Tailwind CSS.
- Built with User Authentication using JWT Tokens and passwords are hashed with Bcrypt.
- Implemented a Centralized Workflow Git control with a team of 5 during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.

Rick and Morty Frontend Project | [GitHub] | [Deployed] | React

(10/2022 - 10/2022)

Rick and morty API with characters, episodes and location info

- Implemented Axios to perform get() request to the Rick and Morty API
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using Style-Components module for React.
- Created a dynamic search bar component that can filter through 3 different endpoints.

What's that fish API [GitHub]

(09/2022 - 9/2022)

Main interactive hub for hosting my projects

- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Deployed API to help users identify the type of seafood they are eating and their nutritional values.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Commercial Line Underwriter | USI | Staten Island, NY/Remote

(07/2019 - 07/2022)

- Core member in the company's new team for the North East Division.
- Managed an extensive list of over 20 different type of clients from day cares to manufacturers
- Analyzed over 15+ carriers to maximized coverage for the client and profit for the companies.
- Collaborated with internal teams to cross sell multiple products to maximize profit and coverage for the client.

Commercial Line Underwriter | Regency Insurance Brokerage Services | Staten Island, NY

(07/2015 - 07/2019)

- Generated \$200,000+ monthly bound new business premium with amazing profit to loss ratio
- Created manuals, documents, and procedures to streamline training new hires and quoting accounts.
- Trained over 5+ assistants on company's procedures and carrier's guidelines.
- Refined the team's monthly data and marketing pamphlets for presentations, meetings and conventions.
- Organized and closed over 100+ outstanding inspection reports.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive | New York, NY John Jay of Criminal Justice College, B.S. | New York, NY

(09/2022 - 12/2022)